Felipe Jonas Rodrigues

Giovani Atílio Tolaine Av., 99 - ap. 33, BL1 - Votupoca - Barueri - SP

Cel (11) 9.7154-7091 - Res (11) 4201-1912 | fjonasr@gmail.com |

https://www.linkedin.com/in/felipejonasrodrigues/

36 years, Brazilian, Married

PERSONAL SUMMARY

I am a professional with more than 12 years of experience in IT, working in engineering, national and international projects, support in critical infrastructure and information security environments, pre-sales, training and speaking to audiences over 100 people.

I have solid knowledge in:

- ✓ Cisco switches (Nexus and Catalyst), Huawei and Juniper switches;
- ✓ CheckPoint and Juniper Firewalls;
- √ F5 balancers in LTM, GTM and irules modules;
- ✓ Proxy Blue Coat;
- ✓ CASB (Cloud Access Security Broker);
- ✓ APT Fireeye and Trend tools;
- ✓ IPS SourceFire;
- ✓ Protection against attacks using Anti-DDOS tools;
- ✓ Digital Certificates (SSL);
- ✓ Docker, Ansible, Puppet, Jenkins, Rundeck and Git tools for automation and CI / CD.

Experience in the creation, implementation and improvement of security and networks norms and procedures and actions to reduce costs.

Integrative leadership and team management to deliver better deliverables in both quality and statistics.

LANGUAGES SKILLS

Portuguese: Native Language

English: Advanced

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

MBA Network Project Management – IBTA – 2012 Bachelor of Engineering – Anhembi Morumbi University – 2007 Electronic Technician – E.T.E. Prof^o Horácio Augusto da Silveira - 2000

CERTIFICATIONS

ISO 27001

Certified Ethical Hacker - CEH - ECC09772775872

Checkpoint Certified Security Administrator - CCSA

Cisco Certified Network Professional R&S - CCNP - CSCO11182471

Cisco Certified Network Associate R&S - CCNA - CSCO11182471

Blue Coat Certified ProxySG Administrator - BCCPA

Redback Networks – SmartEdge Foundation

Redback Networks - SmartEdge PTA

D-LINK - DPC-SWITCH

D-LINK - DPC-WIRELESS

D-LINK - DBCex

COURSES

CEH – Certificação Ethical Hacker v9 – Strong Security

CTR Cyber Threat Response V2.0 - CISCO

DCUFD - Designing Cisco Data Center Unified Fabric 3.0 - HDS

Fundamentals of Incident Handling - Cert.br

Agile infrastructure with DEVOPS practices using Docker, Git, Jenkins, Puppet and Ansible - 4Linux

JNCIA - Juniper Networks Certified Associate – CYLK

JSEC - Junos Security - CYLK

Ericsson Response Volunteer Training (ERV) that assists the Red Cross and UN (conducted in Sweden)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Cielo - 08/2012 - Present

IT Infrastructure Specialist

- Creation and implementation of security and networks standards and procedures and actions to reduce costs;
- ✓ Active participation in the PCI certification process, acting directly with the auditor, providing all the necessary evidence and implementing the agreed controls and recommendations;
- Responsible for defining, coordinating and implementing Network and Security for Data Center and corporate projects using the following technologies:
 - ✓ Cisco Nexus and Catalyst, CheckPoint Firewalls, F5 Balancers;
 ✓ Cloud AWS;
 ✓ Openshift;

 - ✓ APT Tools, Fireeye and Trend;
 - ✓ IPS SourceFire;
 - ✓ Proxy Bluecoat, CASB Bluecoat;
 - ✓ Links anti-DDoS (Clean Pipe);
 - Management of configuration and inventory of network equipment and DNS Infoblox (NETMRI and IPAM):
- Support in critical environments, generating greater profitability to the company, working with solutions in VPC, Fabric Path, EIGRP, BGP, OSPF, VPN, NAT and SSL digital certificates;
- ✓ Conduction of PoCs for Telecom and Security solutions;
- Elaboration and evaluation of network and security RFPs for corporate and transactional environment;
- ✓ Management of third party teams.

Voith - 08/2011 - 08/2012

Network Engineer

- ✓ LAN and WAN network management and operation;
- ✓ Support 3rd level;
 ✓ Administration, Design, Implementation and Support of Cisco routers, Cisco switches, Firewall Checkpoint;
- ✓ Configuration and troubleshooting of Layer2 and Layer3 elements;
- Management of WAN (Branch-Matrix) connections through the MPLS cloud;
- ✓ Coordination of partner companies for the execution of network infrastructure.

WippZ - 03/2011 - 11/2011

Solutions architect

- ✓ Architect of solutions and design for IP network;
- ✓ IP network project management;
- ✓ Entrepreneurship.

Huawei - 10/2010 - 08/2011

Telecommunications Engineer

- ✓ Administration, Design, Implementation and Support of routers CISCO and Huawei, Huawei Firewalls, Huawei Switches and Huawei DPI;
- ✓ Configuration and troubleshooting of Layer2 and Layer3 elements;
- ✓ Coordination of the infrastructure team;
- ✓ Creation of HLD and LLD documentation.

Ericsson - 07/2006 - 10/2010

Telecommunication Engineer

- ✓ Management and maintenance of the IP network of NOC São Paulo and NOC Dallas USA, work done remotely and on-site (4 month project in Dallas);
- ✓ Administration of CISCO and Juniper routers, CISCO and Netscreen Firewalls, Extreme Switches, Juniper SSLVPN:
- ✓ Configuration and problem solving of Layer2 and Layer3 elements of NOCs;
- ✓ Support level 1 and level 2;
- ✓ Participation in Ericsson's Response Volunteer Program (ERV) which assists Red Cross and UN programs (training in Sweden);
- Monitoring and troubleshooting of cellular and 3G network elements, RBS / NodeB / BSC / RNC / MSC / SGSN;
- ✓ Development of monitoring tools and services such as Nagios, FTP-Server, DHCP Server and Active Directory;
- ✓ RedBack consultant for a Vivo 3G network and training for teams to operate the equipment;
- ✓ Internal training of network functions and best practices.

D-Link Brasil - 07/2005 - 07/2006

Telecommunication Engineering Trainee

- ✓ Testing and projects in networks and data communication;
- ✓ Studies and projects to implement or customize equipment for the Brazilian market;
- ✓ Pre-sales technical support, tests with VoIP equipment, ADSL, switches, PLC, Wi-Fi.

Universidade Anhembi Morumbi - 10/2001 - 07/2005 Computer Technician

✓ Computer maintenance, network configuration and software and hardware support for students and teachers.